Mumble

Day 00452: Wednesday, 2016 June 01

The first thing on my agenda for the day was to go out and pay my mobile bill, though honestly, I'm not sure how much longer I'll keep the service. With my mobile failing to function correctly, there's not much point in my carrying it with me, and if I'm not going to carry it with me, there's no point in paying for service. I don't think that I'll be getting a new one either. It's been nice having one especially at first, and I can't say that it hasn't been a learning experience. However, I'm not sure that it's worth the money to get a new one. Replicant doesn't exactly run on low-end devices and vanilla Android isn't exactly useful, secure, or trustworthy. After paying my bill at the game store that doubles as a mobile shop, the cashier told me that if I got an account with the game shop, I could later earn points by paying my bill that could be spent on paying my bill again instead of spending cash. Normally, I would have turned that offer down as I don't want to be tracked, but the game store can already track me through my mobile account. There's no privacy lost that wasn't lost already, so I agreed to the account.

University of [REDACTED] wrote to me today saying that my application is now under review and I will hear back from them by August 4. I anxiously await a response, be it an acceptance or a denial.

It seems that an exploit was discovered in Gogs. In response, Volatile Git shut down indefinitely, only to be reopened once the security issues at hand were better understood, and if need be, patched. It was believed that it was possible to retrieve the password hash database. Luckily, research didn't seem to take as long as I'd have expected and the SQL interface issue was deemed by wowaname to be not a threat and Volatile Git was reopened the same day that it went down.

I tried reinstalling Replicant in hopes that maybe a bit or two had gotten mistakingly flipped, breaking Ext4 support. The mobile does get jostled around a lot and that can't be good for it. However, the reinstallation did nothing more than disable Xposed and orWall, though orWall automatically restored the scripts that would allow it to be re-enabled next time the device rebooted. I'm not sure what else to try.

Emacsite on freenode recommended that I try Mumble, and seemed pretty excited that I'd give it a try. I wasn't overly excited myself as I was busy, but I didn't want to discourage them, so installed Mumble and connected to the Mumble server that they use. It was an interesting experience for sure, but Mumble isn't right for me. It seems that Mumble allows you to either speak or type, but to know what everyone is saying, you need to both listen and read. The sound is distracting and severely cuts my efficiency. For someone like me, IRC is a much better communication medium.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Delicious potato gnocchi

Day 00453: Thursday, 2016 June 02

When the landlords came the other day and mowed the lawn, I noticed right away that the the lawn was now brown. Today I noticed that they also took out the beautiful leafy plant in the corner of the flowerbed by the stairs as well as the other three or so of the same kind in the back flowerbed. That's kind of sad, those plants looked great there. It's strange that the landlords would rather have an empty flowerbed.

I finally took the cans and bottles back for deposit. I'm probably the only one in the house that doesn't drink soda, but no one else really wants to take them back. The deposit machines at the big box store are much nicer than the ones at the closer grocery store! I usually take them back to the grocery store, but I didn't want to deal with the constant jamming of the machines and decided to take a chance with the machines at the big box store today. Next time, I know right were to take them! I should take them sooner though, biking over with several large bags is a pain.

When my mother arrived home, they wanted to go out to eat with someone. They had bought a certificate for food at one of the local restaurants, so since Vanessa doesn't like that restaurant, they took me instead. There were two menu items that looked edible, and my plan was to choose the cheaper item, spaghetti. However, my mother only used half of the value of the certificate and any unused portion of the certificate would be forfeited. Instead, I went with the more expensive item that sounded better, potato gnocchi. This stuff turned out to be even better than the gnocchi that I sometimes buy at the store! The marinara on it wasn't great, but the pasta itself was full of delicious herbs. I wonder if I can make something similar myself (though not until I move out as my mother can't stand the smell of my cooking).

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Flash mob and relatives

Day 00455: Saturday, 2016 June 04

I'm giving up trying to get Ext4 SD cards to work in my broken mobile for now. I've formatted one of the SD cards as stupid FAT. It's not feasible to make a second copy of my music library and go through the copy to find all the files with names that FAT is too moronic to allow (such as those with question marks), so I'm just going to have to leave those files off of my mobile for now. Once I have time and get Ext4 support working again, I'll have my full library back. It seems that in addition to disallowing the use of certain characters in file names, FAT also disallows even more characters *as* file names. I keep the songs that don't have album name meta data in a directory with a name consisting of only a single space; FAT doesn't like that. This is idiotic. If FAT can handle spaces *in* file names, why can't it handle a space *as* a file name? It looks like I won't be storing any loose songs on FAT, only songs from albums. I hate FAT. In addition to losing access to all the albumless songs, I'm also losing eleven whole albums and several individual songs from albums. I can't wait to have Ext4 support back.

As a side note, if I remove the SD card from the mobile and insert it in my laptop, PCManFM has this awesome feature where it'll halt the file-transfer process each time that it comes across a file name that the file system (in this case FAT) is too stupid to handle. Each time it stops like this, it allows the computer user to choose a new file name! This on-the-fly renaming is perfect for this type of situation. I'm loving PCManFM; Thunar doesn't have this capability. However, this functionality isn't available over MTP. Removing the card from the mobile is a pain because of the protective case, so I won't do that for now.

My mother and I participated in a flash mob today, which was more fun that I though that it'd be. We stood around in a circle playing a strange game. We started with a ball of cellophane with candy wrapped within it periodically. One person would rip it apart trying to pull out as many candies as possible while another would repeatedly roll a die until they got a one. At that point, they'd pass the die onto the next person and take the ball of cellophane to try pulling candy out of it themselves. That went on for a few rounds until the cellophane ball was no more. Before parting from the group, everyone was then given a Pathtag representing the event.

After that, my mother and I spent most of the day working in my mother's classroom, then went out looking for yard sales for a little while. While we were out, I managed to finish cracking the combination on a lock that I'd found at home: 748. No one knew the combination so we were going to get rid of it, but we couldn't add it to our yard sale because we can't sell a lock without a combination. I started fiddling with it whenever we go out and I remember. I just started at 000 and incremented by one each time. The fact that I could even do that means that the lock design isn't very secure though, so even now that we have the combination, I'm not sure we'll find a use for the lock.

It turns out that relatives aren't coming over. Instead, they rented a house in town. We met them at a restaurant to eat, but then we stayed at the restaurant for what felt like forever. I was exhausted by the time we left and the restaurant workers had closed the restaurant quite a while ago. These people (and my mother) can talk for ages!

It seems that my mother needs help dealing with students during a field trip, so they've recruited me. On Tuesday, I'll be leading a group of four or five first grade students through a tour of some tide pools. I'm not sure how I feel about this, but it'll be a new experience.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Threats

Day 00456: Sunday, 2016 June 05

Late last night, a friend that prefers not to be mentioned by name quoted my journal, alerting wowaname to how disgruntled that I was about being banned from #Volatile. At the time, I thought that they were trying to stir up trouble, but by the end of today, I decided that it was likely an attempt to bring the situation to light and resolve the unspoken conflict. After the discussion that this started, it was decided that I don't belong at Volatile. I suppose I always knew that I don't fit in there, but it is still with much sadness that I take my leave. The simple fact is that Volatile was built as a troll nest. Wowaname says that they grew up on the trollish side of the Internet, so it makes sense that the network that they set up would take on such traits. On the other hand, I grew up on a much more polite and tolerant side of the Internet. We didn't pick on people, we didn't flood out all conversation, and we certainly didn't penalize people for technical difficulties. In the forums that I used, it was rude to even double post, let alone flood the page. Rather, people were expected to edit their own posts to add on if someone else hadn't spoken yet. Maybe one day, I'll find an IRC network/channel that fits me. Something similar to the Floraverse IRC channel would be nice, but wowaname got me (as well as the rest of the Tor network) banned there. I'd love to blame wowaname for that, but the simple fact is that anywhere that would ban the whole Tor network certainly isn't where I belong. This network isn't where I should be hanging out either.

Wowaname somehow views one join and one part every ten minutes as "flooding tastelessly", but somehow doesn't see that a ten-minute bombardment of Unicode art that halts and interrupts all conversation is far more tasteless. Our viewpoints simply aren't compatible. I tolerated the Unicode art, but it seems that wowaname can't tolerate basic technical difficulties. They said that they'd understand if I don't want to come back to their network, though strangely, I do want to come back. The simple fact is though that it doesn't matter what I want; I'm not wanted there. It's time for me to let go and move on.

After establishing the fact that I don't belong there and that I shouldn't return, wowaname later oddly brought up that the ping interval is ten minutes. This ping interval could be the cause of my ten-minute cycle; Tor might not be the cause. Why were they continuing to diagnose the "problem" when it was no longer relevant? There's nothing to fix, I'm already gone.

My mother and I went to Springfield to pick up Vanessa and Cyrus. Along the way, traffic came to a complete halt for a bit. It turns out that there had been an accident; an automobile had been flipped on its side, blocking one and a half lanes of the two-lane highway. The windshield was smashed up as well, though I didn't get a good look at it. With only half a lane available, and that half lane being needed for traffic in both directions, the huge line of traffic on each side needed to be stopped to allow the other side to get through for a while. On the way back, the scene had been cleaned up already. If there were any fatalities, investigation would have probably taken longer, so our best guess is that everyone was relatively fine.

That bit of apparent good news was the only pleasant part of the trip home though. Our mother started telling off Cyrus and Vanessa and even threatening them. Our mother says There's no changing evil., and they strongly believe that our father is evil. They said that unless Cyrus skips the yearly trip to see our paternal grandfather, they will boot Cyrus from our household. Cyrus is to spend that time trying to find a job instead. Cyrus also needs to work on college applications, which they have been neglecting. Unfortunately, child support will end if Cyrus cannot fill out paperwork telling what college they are attending, so if they aren't attending college yet, there'll be a problem. As for Vanessa, our mother was threatening them saying that they were going to send them to live with our father permanently unless Vanessa looks into what needs to be done to legally go against the judge's visitation orders and stop visiting our father. Vanessa's lack of ability to tell people what they don't want to hear had resulted in them telling each parent a different story about what they wanted, which turned out badly in court; child support has been cut and Vanessa will be spending two more weeks each summer with our father, which supposedly they don't want. It's not that Vanessa doesn't want to see our father, just that supposedly they don't want added visitation time over what was scheduled originally. This inability to speak their actual mind though is likely caused by our mother. Our mother berates us if we have any ideas that don't match their own. The only safe option is often to hide all sign of having an opinion or to pretend to have an identical (or at least similar) opinion. It really isn't healthy.

Once back in town, the four of us headed over to see our relatives that are renting a house locally through today. Three of these people are relatives by blood, while two are part of the group because of relationships. We ate and talked, and I see that our sense of humor is either genetic or learned; perhaps both. Everyone there seemed to think very similarly and while we all laughed and had a good time. Cyrus asked for the email address of our cousin and their lover, so I asked to be in on that email address exchange as well.

Once home, I needed to do something semi-mindless to clear my thoughts, to I played SuperTux for a bit. I quickly found a bug, though only a minor one, so hopefully that can be fixed by the next stable release. It looks like a pretty simple fix if you know what you're doing; one of the area markers is a bit too tall. Stable releases are few and far between, so there should be plenty of time.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Tide pool trip

Day 00458: Tuesday, 2016 June 07

When we arrived at the school this morning, I signed in as a volunteer using the school's computer system. My name was on the list of people that one could sign in as, so my background check must have come back clean. It would have been nice if the school had had the courtesy to actually tell me that though, instead of waiting for me to try to sign in. At the very least, they should have sent me an email soon after performing the background check. My mother had to attend a meeting before the field trip, so I retrieved the student lunches from the cafeteria and waited in the classroom on my laptop. I thought that I'd have time to get a bit of work done, but the meeting didn't drag on like I thought that it would.

As we boarded the bus, I reminded my mother to bring medication for one of her students as they'd asked me to, then took a seat. The seating on the bus was tiny, seeing as it was built only to accommodate elementary schoolers, and the trip was quite noisy. The children talked amongst themselves in a deafening roar, though once we'd reached our destination, one of the teachers remarked about how quiet that they'd been. I guess that they're usually even louder! My mother said that they'd work on deciding who lead what groups on the bus, but then assigned me no group once we got there. Apparently, more volunteers came than had let us know that they'd be coming, so there were too few groups for the volunteers present. My mother had to have known this before I'd boarded the bus. Why didn't they let me know so I could stay behind? My presence on the trip was completely pointless, I wasn't able to help at all, and I wasted half the day at the tide pools when I could have been catching up on stuff that I'm behind on - or I could have even just rested my knees. The uneven terrain wasn't good on my sore knees, and my upper left leg is now sore. Once we got back to the school, my mother had another meeting and no task for me, so I walked home.

It seems that professional landscapers will be coming over to work on the yard on the fourteenth.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mother is seriously good at denial.

Day 00462: Saturday, 2016 June 11

Vivian gave me some vegan fake cheese today. They had bought it because it's dairy-free and milk is one of the things that they've had to eliminate from their diet for now, but the fake cheese makes Vivian's stomach hurt. New foods do that to them sometimes, and they do plan to go back to eating dairy, so getting used to the fake cheese wasn't worth it to them.

I received a second voter registration card in the mail today. At first I thought that Cyrus had registered and this was their card, and once I realized that it was mine, I was confused for a bit. The government probably sent this new card because of my mandatory registration update though. I can only assume that receipt of this card means that my vote has been accepted now and will be counted.

I also received a letter from my health care provider. They say that they (not my insurance provider or dental health care provider) will now pay for stainless steel crowns on molars now, and that this may result in teeth that would have needed to be pulled being saved instead. I'd like to think that my dentist would have mentioned that I could get crowns if I paid for them out of pocket instead of getting my teeth pulled if that was an option in my case. I wouldn't be able to afford this probably, but I should be made aware of the option in case I did have the resources and they didn't know about it. I'm going to be a bit peeved if this isn't the case. However, I'll go in and ask them about the letter and my teeth on Monday. I'd much rather have metal-capped teeth than missing teeth. They'd probably even be more durable than the originals. However, it might not matter what they say. I won't be in town for my appointment, most likely. It matters less that these people can save my teeth than that my next dental care providers can save them.

We arrived at Cyrus' and Vanessa's school an hour early for Cyrus' graduation ceremony. After that, the ceremony was two hours long. It was a painfully-boring waste of time. There's a reason that I didn't attend my own graduation ceremony. Today's graduation ceremony began with an agonizingly-slow and awkward walk by the graduates, as they moved toward their seats in what could be likened to a slow-motion skipping motion. We were expected to stand through this entire process, which is never easy on my legs, even when my knees aren't on the mend. When that was finally complete, a few speeches were made and several groups of people were called out, but it was an hour and forty minutes of wasted time. They even had a choir sing. We weren't there to listen to a choir! In the remaining twenty minutes of the ceremony, they finally called people up and handed out diplomas, which was the only fast-paced part of the whole ordeal.

On the way home, our mother was trying to get Cyrus to choose where we had dinner, as Cyrus had just graduated and our mother is very much into commemorating everything. Cyrus was trying to choose something that Vivian could eat, which was difficult for them. Cyrus doesn't usually have to pay attention to what's in food as they're not on any special diet, but Vivian is vegetarian and is on further doctor-prescribed dietary restrictions for diagnostic reasons. Cyrus mentioned that they weren't sure if Mexican food would work because the beans might contain lard, but that confused our mother as they didn't remember lard being on the doctor-prescribed list of foods to avoid. Cyrus brought up that Vivian is also has their usual vegetarian dietary restrictions, which sparked a heated discussion. Our mother knew that Vivian wanted to be a vegetarian as early as high school, but our mother put a stop to that by force. They thought that the issue was dealt with and therefore wouldn't come up again, but failed to account for the fact that they had never actually convinced Vivian of anything, or even honestly *tried* to convince Vivian of anything. Vivian even said before they moved out and went to college that as soon as they moved out, they would go back to being a vegetarian. Our mother has been in denial, somehow becoming blissfully unaware that Vivian still detests having to eat meat.

The discussion didn't end there though, and our mother told Vivian to never have children, to which Vivian replied that they already were planning not to. This caused our mother to get even stranger, saying that they didn't understand why anyone would ever choose not to have babies. Our mother just can't get over the fact that at least two of their children won't have children of their own. Perhaps our mother wants grandchildren or perhaps they want their DNA to live on. I think instead though that our mother takes it as a personal insult, as our mother takes any choice that doesn't match their own as an attack on their own character. They don't understand the concept of "live and let live" or "to each their own". Next, our mother railed on Vivian's boyfriend. Vivian's boyfriend never visits when our mother and Vivian are together, the reason being that our mother doesn't like Vivian's boyfriend, so Vivian's boyfriend stays away. However, our mother loves using this as ammunition, saying that Vivian's boyfriend is never around and is therefore not a good boyfriend. No matter how many times this is explained to our mother, they just don't get it and the dislike continues. At this point, I left the room to give them a bit of privacy. I really wish that our mother wasn't such a control freak about everything.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Cobra lilies

Day 00463: Sunday, 2016 June 12

Today was mostly spent fulfilling social obligations. I hung out with my family, which in today's state of mind, wasn't too bad. Alyssa gave me her gluten-free English muffins because they were too dry. They were surprisingly dry, but they're good with vinegar. I can't be too picky, it's harder to get edible bread here than it is in Springfield. There is a store that sells bread without animal products, but it's a bit distant from home.

After a while, we went on a short road trip. The first main stop was a vegetation preserve that held "darlingtonia" that our mother wanted to show us. I had no idea what these were, besides that they were carnivorous plants. As it turns out, "darlingtonia" is the genus name of the spices darlingtonia californica, a plant more commonly known as cobra lilies, cobra orchids, or pitcher plants. If I'd heard the term "pitcher plant", I'd have had a much better idea of what the plant was, but I like the name "cobra lilies" better. The "heads" of these plants very much do look like cobras with their hoods flared out, especially when brown and dying. I took a photograph of a patch of green and brown pitchers, but as my camera has been blurry for quite some time, it's not really usable. Take a look at the photos on the Wikipedia page if you're interested.

The other main stop was at some dude's grave. Unlike the first stop, this one was pretty uneventful. I guess this guy is a well-known part of Oregon history, but as far as I know, they were only a famous runner. It's not like they made an important difference in the world, or even in the state. To the best of my knowledge, they are simply another celebrity to ignore like any other celebrity.

After this short road trip, we headed to the hills to pick up bullet shells. Along the way, our mother told Alyssa a story told to us by our relatives during our recent visit with them, but as usual, couldn't keep chronology straight, mixing up the cause and the effect. It wasn't a big deal of course, but it made the story make little sense. It should serve as a reminder to me that they can't keep chronology or cause and effect straight though, so I shouldn't take take their word on that sort of thing when what they say contradicts my own memory.

Alyssa offered me some old calendars that talk about how the volunteer organization that Alyssa works with works, but they had the same information as the one that they already gave me. They grabbed the calendars in a rush and didn't know that they were mostly the same aside from the artwork, so explained that they turned out to be the same and weren't surprised when I turned the calendars down. I need to thin down further, not add more items to my ownership. Also, it seems that Alyssa has been migraine-free for a couple days, likely due to the supplements that they've just started taking. Hopefully these pain-free days continue and the supplements are all that are needed.

While we were all sitting down and resting from our trip, I leaned over to pet the cat and the computer chair that I was sitting on broke in front of everyone. One of the five wheeled legs snapped, rendering the chair unusable. That was a bit embarrassing. I suppose that that's one less chair that needs to be moved to our new house though.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Censorship

Day 00464: Monday, 2016 June 13

My plan for today was to return bottles for deposit and talk to the people at my dentist's office about crowns, but Vivian is unexpectedly still here. I had assumed that they'd be visiting only for the weekend, but they're actually here until Thursday. Errands can wait.

While our mother was at work and Vanessa was at school, Vivian and I talked about what has been going on in their life. People have been finding lead in water in Portland, which is kind of scary. Worse still, one of the schools that was found to have lead didn't admit to there being lead in their water until *after* they'd fixed it. They were allowing the students to continue drinking it without so much as warning them! Vivian is also now part of a union, but not by choice. It seems that in Oregon, if there's a union related to your field in your area, you're in it whether you like it or not. A new such union has formed in Portland. Vivian is against unions due to how regulated they are by the government. According to Vivian, unions push down the lower class in an effort to raise the middle class. Instead, Vivian prefers the group that they choose to work with, which tries to raise the lower class, an attempt to bring everyone closer to equality.

Vivian claims that one of the books that they bought is illegal to own in this country. That's kind of scary. Assuming that they're right, the fact that the book is illegal, even though it's purely for peaceful education, is some major censorship. Even a non-peaceful book shouldn't be illegal to own, but the government doesn't even have the excuse of "trying to protect the peace" with this one. My understanding is that there is an edition of this book that's legal here, but that for some reason, these localized books are illegal outside the country that they are released to. I was curious and wanted to look up information on this, but I felt it best that I not not know what book it was, so I didn't ask. The less I know, the less that information could be turned against my sibling.

Vivian, Cyrus, Vanessa, our mother, and I worked in our mother's classroom for about half the day, boxing things to move out. Not only will we need to clear our stuff from our rented home, but also from the classroom. Many teaching aids of various types were brought in near the beginning. What many people fail to realize is that schoolteachers often spend a lot of their own money on resources for use with their job. As our mother won't be working there next year, we need to haul it with us to their new job, once that job is found.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The school blocks Tor!

Day 00465: Tuesday, 2016 June 14

Vivian sent me out to run errands this morning. I needed to get photographs printed for Vanessa, buy playing cards for Vanessa, and pick up salad for Vivian. It seemed like an easy enough task, though I quickly found that my bicycle brakes had stopped working! It was raining, and it seems that my brakes fail to have any effect when wet. Riding down the hill into town was not at all pleasant! Just to travel at a somewhat-safe speed, I dragged one of my feet on the pavement. While that succeeded in slowing my descent, it couldn't have been good for my already-tattered shoes. The rain stopped after I picked up the playing cards, so I stopped for breakfast to give the brakes time to dry off. With my brakes functioning again, I headed to the next location. I still had errands, so I only ate part of my breakfast, saving the rest for later.

The photography center of the store required that I insert the SD card in a provided computer, choose the photographs to print, then enter some information about myself. A first and last name were required, along with a telephone number. An email address was optional. I of course entered my first and last name along with my email address, leaving the telephone number field blank. The machine demanded that I add a telephone number, so I went to go get help from one of the employees. I suspected that a bogus telephone number could be used, but the more attention that is drawn to this type of problem, the more likely it has a chance of getting fixed. The employee quickly dismissed the problem, just entering a telephone number consisting of ten sixes. The machine complained about this, stating that the telephone number must be valid! They tried entering a couple other random numbers before they found one that the machine would accept. Once a number was accepted, the computer complained that my real email address was invalid! They just deleted my email address from the form, and the machine accepted the submission. While the photographs seemed to be printed almost right away, they people running the photography center required that I wait an hour before I retrieved them. With nothing better to do for an hour, I sat down and finished my food.

On the way home, I found a black and silver ring, too small to fit on even my smallest finger. It wasn't overly-fancy, it might have been tungsten or titanium. It was the perfect size for my mother though, so I gave it to them.

Vivian, Vanessa, Cyrus, our mother, and I worked in our mother's classroom again today, but there wasn't much that we could get done. Our mother was the only one that knew what needed to be done, but was too frazzled to delegate well. They mentioned that their school computer doesn't output sound any more, so I tried to debug that issue while I waited for actual instructions on how to help. Testing revealed that the problem wasn't the speakers, as the speakers worked with my mobile and my headphones didn't work with the computer. The computer had an option to troubleshoot sound problems, but it required the administrative password, so I got nowhere. Stupid Windows. Why would one need administrative approval to alter sound settings? Sound settings should be on a per-account basis, so administrative action shouldn't be involved. I'm not going to try to debug administrative problems on Windows and didn't have the password anyway, so I gave up.

Our mother officially put in their resignation today. They were crying. Not only is it difficult to leave a job, but also, they don't have their new job found yet. They're worried for the future, but need to get out of this awful place. The people in this small and poverty-stricken town are awful to each other and to our mother. Our mother also wants to get back into the valley and live closer to relatives.

Mary-Margaret, one of the kindergarten teachers, asked Cyrus and me if we'd burn photographs onto CDs for them, so we agreed to do it. Getting our mother's classroom cleaned out was our main priority, but there were too many bodies and not enough labor; we wouldn't be missed. Mary-Margaret wasn't quite ready for us, though word that there were people willing to help got out quickly. Another teacher (one that I don't know) approached us and asked us to take down everything from their bulletin board. We completed that task, then were soon re-approached by Mary-Margaret, who was now ready. For some reason, Cyrus stayed behind, so I headed to the computer lab with Mary-Margaret alone. Once there, we found that there were too many photographs to store on the "CDs", which turned out to be DVDs, so Mary-Margaret went through and deleted some. Some were just unneeded, but others were outright duplicates, added accidentally. We found that we only had one DVD, so we were going to test the burning process with it before Mary-Margaret went out to buy more DVDs, but that DVD turned out to already be written to. Furthermore, it seems that most of the computers in the computer lab lack optical drives for some reason. Of the about forty-eight computers available, only four have DVD drives!

Mary-Margaret and Cyrus went out to buy food and DVDs for burning. They brought back pizza and a vegetable tray. I was hungry, but decided to complete my DVD-burning task before eating.

With blank DVDs in hand, I headed back to the computer lab and tried to insert a blank DVD into each of the four machines to burn multiple DVDs in parallel. One of the DVD drives wouldn't open though, leaving me with only three machines to work with. Stupidly, I tried burning the first DVD directly from files on the USB drive containing the photographs instead of copying the files to the machine first. As such, I wasn't able to start the next burning until the first completed. This turned out to be for the best though, as the Windows computers in the computer lab were being idiotic as Windows computers always do. This time, the burning process was split into two parts. In the first part, the files were indexed and prepared for burning, regardless of whether they fit on the DVD or not. Upon manually starting the second step (which took a while to even figure out how to do), the computer would actually perform the check to see if the files would fit, like it already should have done when adding the files to the queue. It turned out that there were still too many photographs to start the burn, as while Mary-Margaret had gotten the total file sizes below four point seven gigabytes, the actual file system size on the DVD is smaller than that. I'm not sure if this is because of data in the file system that takes up space but isn't used for files themselves or if the DVD's advertised size is measured incorrectly; hardware manufacturers often use a smaller unit that they claim are "gigabytes", just to make their products look better than they actually are. In either case, I went through the remaining photographs myself, deleting the duplicates that Mary-Margaret had missed (they quit looking for duplicates once the total size was believed to be small enough), and the size was brought down within the limits of what would fit. This time, I did copy the files to each of the three machines, then started the burning process.

Between changing out DVDs and restarting the burning process, I tried to get the DVD labels created. The label package said that there was a label template online, so I tried downloading that. I ran into several problems along the way. First, I needed some privacy. I wasn't doing anything that I wasn't supposed to, but I won't browse the Web without Tor. I tried to reach the Tor Project website, but the school blocks access to that! I knew about the Tor Project's mirror on GitHub for people that can't reach the Tor Project website directly, so I went there. The thing about the GitHub mirror is that it's next to impossible to block without blocking all of GitHub. Due to GitHub's use of TLS, most blocking software won't even see what pages are requested, and those that do will cause "bad certificate" errors, so all decent websites don't work as well. Once I had the Tor Browser Bundle downloaded, I found that the school computer blocked its installation. I assumed that it was an issue of modification of system directories, though that later turned out not to be the case. The install was successful when I had it install in the downloads directory instead of the default location though. Next, I found that the school network also blocks the Tor network itself! This was my first opportunity to work with Tor bridges in an environment where their use was actually warranted. The setup was surprisingly easy. I thought that I'd need to look up some bridges from a bridge information distribution system on the Web, but the Tor Browser Bundle did everything automatically once I told it that a bridge was needed. The next issue was the website that actually held the template. It required a name and email address be given in order to download the template needed to make use of the product that had already been paid for! If the template was at least under a free license, I'd have been more than happy to supply these, but as it were, I didn't want this company having any of my email addresses. I'd only be using the template on behalf of Mary-Margaret. I wasn't sure if the template would be sent via email or if the email address would be verified, so I used an identity generator, which worked out nicely. However, the site wanted to send me a Windows executable file instead of the actual template! What a mess. You can never trust Windows executable files on a Windows machine. At a loss as to what to do and about to give up on the labels, I spotted a pair of radio buttons on the page. It seems that by default, the website tries to trick you into installing a toolbar when downloading the template! Clicking on the other radio button, the download link changed instead to one pointing at the template and the template alone: a DOC file. There was no way that I was going to work on Microsoft Office, so my next step was to download LibreOffice. That download took *forever*. By the time I had it downloaded, it was almost time to go. Strangely, the LibreOffice website asks for a donation, but requires that one fill out a CAPTCHA before one can comply. CAPTCHAs are annoying, I'm certainly not going to donate if I can't do so without solving one. When I tried to install LibreOffice, the installation unexpectedly worked. I figured it'd fail just like the initial Tor Browser Bundle installation. Does that mean that the school specifically blocks installations into the default directory used by the Tor Browser Bundle in an effort to prevent Tor use? I'm not sure what else the issue would be. After the installation, my mother came in and said that it was time to leave. I gave Mary-Margaret back the twenty-eight burnt DVDs that they wanted along with all the remaining blanks. While I didn't get the labels done, the DVD burning was complete.

I headed back to the classroom so we could gather up our stuff and head out, and I found that the vegetable tray was completely finished off. Everyone had finished it off, leaving only pizza. Sadly, I missed out on getting anything to eat, but once we finished unloading at home, I was able to make a salad. Strangely, the landscapers that were supposed to come today never showed. I mean, we weren't around to see them, but there's also no sign that anything has been done. I wonder if they were called off for some reason.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mobile is dying.

Day 00466: Wednesday, 2016 June 15

Vivian, Vanessa, Cyrus, our mother, and I spent most of the day boxing things to take home from the classroom. Aside from our mother, we didn't have any tasks available right away, so I stopped by Mary-Margaret's room to finish up the DVDs by building the labels. However, it seems that it was too late; Mary-Margaret had given out the DVDs to their students already. Technically, the labels hadn't been strictly necessary, but they would have been nice. I felt a bit bad that I waited a while to find the label template. If I'd gotten that downloaded right away, I'd have moved on to downloading LibreOffice sooner. I had no idea that LibreOffice would take so long to download though! I also had a sneaking suspicion that I'd forgotten to return Mary-Margaret's USB drive, so I asked about that. I was right, I'd left it in the computer lab. At least it'd already been returned to them or they'd found it themselves though, so they had it back.

The gym teacher came in and asked if we could put large letters and numbers on paper, ranging from "A1" to "B14". The initial plan was to attempt to write them very neatly, but we quickly decided to instead just type them up on a computer in a clear font. What's the clearest font probably known to man? Monospace! So I typed up a document in LibreOffice on my laptop in Monospace, as I'd brought my laptop this time to use for building the DVD labels. With one letter/number combination on each page, I sent the document to my mother, as my computer isn't hooked up to the school printers. Opening it on the Windows machine did not go as expected though. While the document remained in "Monospace", it wasn't the Monospace that we all know and love. Instead, Microsoft has put some fancy, curvy font with that name into their system! The clarity of the characters was lost and both my mother and the gym teacher questioned my choice in fonts. I showed them what it looked like on my machine though, and they agreed that Monospace (the *real* Monospace, anyway) was the perfect font for the job. They looked through the available fonts on Windows and chose something more reasonable than Windows "Monospace", then printed it. Why would Microsoft do something like this?

Alyssa (the vegan teacher at my mother's school) caught me in the hall and wanted to discuss vegan restaurants that they know of in Eugene. I think that they were trying to recommend them to me, but I'm not in Eugine, so it's not like I'll be stopping by these places any time soon. Likewise, I tend to eat fast food occasionally, but I don't go to sit-down restaurants unless someone else wants to go, and they tend to know where they want to eat already. More interestingly, it seems that Alyssa's been vegan for two years while their partner has been vegan for twenty.

After that, another teacher had Cyrus and I go stack tables in their room. Strangely, one of that teacher's children asked if I was able to speak. What a random question! I then proceeded to pretend that I couldn't speak whenever that child was in the room just to amuse myself. At first, the child didn't seem to believe me. If they weren't going to believe my answer, why did they ask? By the end of the day though, I had them convinced that I was mute.

My mobile's functionality is deteriorating. Now, it keeps losing all the files on the FAT SD card. Combine that with the fact that it can't even read Ext4 SD cards any more, and it's having serious SD card issues. I'm not sure how much longer I want to deal with this. There's got to be a reasonable solution to the problem.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The dead are gone, right?

Day 00467: Thursday, 2016 June 16

At some point before I shut down my mobile for an extended period of time because of the SD card issues, I had to wake up kind of early for something. I forget what it was; it might have been a trip to Springfield. In any case, I set my alarm for 06:00. Since starting the mobile back up, it's woken me up every day at that time because I'm too tired to fix it in the morning after it wakes me up and I don't think about it later in the day. This morning, I shut off the alarm so it'll stop getting me up, but only after it had awoken me from an awful nightmare. I'm glad that the alarm put an end to my misery, though looking back, I would have probably forgotten the dream if my alarm hadn't gone off. After all, we only remember the dreams that waking interrupts, and I'm not sure what else would have gotten me up at that time.

Vivian departed this morning, though not as early as they wanted to. Our mother wanted Vivian to bring some of our junk to store at their place, but wouldn't tell them what to take until this morning, so we couldn't even begin packing the car last night. As Vivian left, they gave me bread, rice, and macaroni with vegan cheese that they didn't want to have to bring back with them.

Today was the last day of school, both for Vanessa and our mother. Cyrus, Vanessa, our mother, and I worked in our mother's classroom most of the day to get our mother out of there. Between jobs, Cyrus, Vanessa, and I drew and wrote goofy things on the whiteboard. For example, Vanessa drew an analogue clock in a square, labeling it "clock in", and an analogue clock outside of a square, labelling that one "clock out"! I decided to write a haiku (this haiku, like the rest of this website, is licensed under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+):

Haikus are easy:
five/seven/five syllables.
Won't you please write one?

Cyrus just wrote down a haiku that they'd heard from a friend, but Vanessa wrote a creative zombie poem:

The dead are gone, right? But not for long, sonny-boy. The dead will soon rise.

Vanessa (Vanessa Desperado) has released this haiku under the CC BY-SA 4.0 license, but has waived the attribution requirement.

Alyssa (the vegan teacher) wanted to talk about veganism for an extended period of time today, though I was anxious to get back to my mother's classroom. Sure, I'm vegan, but there's nothing really that needs to be said about it. They sent me a link to a video via email, then showed me part of another video on their computer. Alyssa talked through part of the video though, and stopped the video about halfway through, so I didn't catch much. The main point though was the importance of getting enough lysine, and Alyssa says that lysine can be found in lentils, garbanzo beans, black beans, and white beans. I should probably work those into my diet more. After that, we worked on cleaning up Alyssa's room while Alyssa discussed several aspects of their own veganism, such as that they don't allow their students to kill bugs and that they always try to bring fancy vegan foods to potlucks in an attempt to dispel the thought that vegan food is either simple fruit or strange substitutes. After a while, I thought I heard my mother yelling for me, so I said my farewell and left.

As it turned out, I hadn't been called. My mind probably generated the sound because I'd been trying to leave for a while but didn't know how to escape. It wasn't that I don't like Alyssa, but I was there to help my mother and I wasn't sure what they'd think of me being gone the whole time. As it turns out, I still wasn't needed and there was still hardly anything for Cyrus, Vanessa, and I to do, so I quickly grew bored and wanted to go back and help Alyssa. I'm always on edge about that type of thing though, as my mother's quite funny. I never know when my mother is going to take something such as my absence as a personal attack, so I stayed in my mother's classroom. In retrospect though, as long as I was being useful to Alyssa, there shouldn't have been an issue. I was there to get stuff done and my mother had nothing for us to do.

On the way home, we stopped at a grocery store, where some sale items were ambiguously labeled. Specifically, there was a sign telling us that mangoes were on sale, but there were a couple different types of mangoes present. We had no way to know which ones were on sale, as the sign didn't match the labels of either mango type, so my mother chose the type that they wanted to be on sale. When checking out, the mangoes came up under the regular price instead of the sale price, so my mother called over an employee (my mother always uses self-checkout, so there wasn't one present already). The employee didn't want to override the price without actually checking the details of the situation, which made my mother angry. The person was only doing their job! They found that it was the other mangoes that were really on sale, and it angered my mother further that they wouldn't give us the sale price on the mangoes that weren't on sale. Yes, it's true that the sale sign should be much more clear about what's actually on sale, but this isn't the fault of the employee that we spoke with and the employee was just doing their job properly by not changing the price for us. It's exactly this sort of bizarre thought pattern that makes me nervous around my mother.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Broken computer

Day 00469: Saturday, 2016 June 18

The teachers at my mother's school are grouped into teams of people that are supposed to support each other, each composed of teachers of a specific grade level. My mother constantly complains that her team hasn't given my mother their telephone numbers. I've asked about this in the past, and my mother has never asked for their telephone numbers, they've just expected the other teachers to volunteer them. Furthermore, my mother has all of their email addresses, so it's not like they can't be reached. My mother's a bit obsessed with telephones though, which is part of where I get my own distaste for them. Today, I finally worked the final question that's been haunting me into the conversation in a non-accusatory way: has my mother ever offered these people *their* telephone number? As it turns out, no, no they have not. My mother expects these other teachers to volunteer extra contact information without actually offering contact information themself. Sure, that's not one-sided or anything. It's true that a lot of the teachers have given each other their telephone numbers, but it's also true that a lot of these teachers have known each other for years and are good friends. They likely have each other's telephone numbers because of off-the-clock interactions. These people don't necessarily even think to try to reach my mother outside of email; if my mother wanted to establish an extra line of communication using the telephone system, my mother should be the one to reach out and offer their number first. Most likely, the other teachers would respond by handing over their own telephone numbers in kind. However, my mother somehow thinks that it's not their own place to do the reaching out, but somehow is the other teachers' responsibility.

My mother was about to head out without me, so I started gathering my stuff to go as quickly as I could. They said that if I came along, it'd be as likely that I'd actually be able to help as that I'd instead end up sitting there bored. Wanting to be there in case any help was needed, I came along anyway, but I made sure to bring my laptop. First, we ended up hitting up some yard sales, and at one of them, we found some kitchen knives for a dime each. Some of these were very nice knives though. We picked up two that had originally come from one of the dollar discount stores. They originally came in a pack of seven for a dollar, but they're the best knives that I've ever used. Seriously. I'm not sure why such quality knives were ever sold so cheaply, but we always buy more whenever we find them second hand. We don't see them in-store any more (I've never seen them in-store, that's how old these things are), but they hold up with age very well and cut fantastically. Next week, we plan to hold our own sale again to try to rid ourselves of more junk.

Once at the school, I predictably didn't have anything to do, so I tried starting my laptop. That didn't go well at all. Simply plugging newdawn.local. into the wall caused it to go into a strange restart loop in which it wouldn't turn on long enough to even reach the BIOS booting screen before shutting off and starting again. It'd just been functioning before I left home! After working the machine over frustrated for a bit, I found that the power supply jack seemed to be pushed in a bit far. Was an improper connection to the charger cord causing the problem? Dismantling my laptop, I found that the power supply jack was indeed out of place; the thin plastic walls holding the jack against the outside of the shell were broken. Hopefully, I'd found the issue. Getting decent access to the problem spot required further dismantling though, so I continued taking things apart. Due to putting pressure on the wrong part of a connector while disconnecting the electronic components, I broke the connector responsible for making my touchpad work! That was frustrating. I also found that the fan was packed with dust, so I cleaned that out while I had the machine open. I went looking for my mother to ask if the school had any electrical tape that they leave lying around, but instead found Mary-Margaret, so I asked them instead. Mary-Margaret lent me their own electrical tape instead! With electrical tape in hand, I bound the power supply jack back into place as best as I could, then started putting the machine back together. I also noted that my RAM slots were full while the machine was open; I'd wondered if I could pack any more RAM into it a while back, as I have many sticks of miscellaneous RAM types lying around. Sadly, I forgot to take note of which of the two wires attached to which spot on what I believe is the Wi-Fi card, but my first guess worked. I'm not sure if both options would have functioned, but I was too tired to test the other option when the first was doing what I needed it to. I'd spent several hours trying to fix my machine, so I was ready to be done with it. Likewise, I'd used up all of my free time. With the laptop fixed, it was time to start loading the van.

We headed to the hills to search for bullet shells. We found many, along with a dead porcupine. It didn't look like the porcupine had been shot, so it probably just died of natural causes. My mother loves parts of dead things though, so they pulled off several hairs and quills. They said they'd cook them to kill off any dangerous bacteria, then use them for education, allowing students to see what porcupine hair and quills look like. In particular, it sounds like they want to show how sharp the quills are and that the hair is multicolored. We were too tired to unload when we got home, so we'll do that tomorrow morning.

My laptop's doing better than before it broke! Specifically, it doesn't seem to overheat any more. The fan being full of junk was no doubt hard on it, so I should remember to open my laptop and clean out the fan again next time that it starts to overheat instead of assuming that the laptop's just old. Does this mean that thinkpad-x60s.local. should be just fine then? I replaced the fan, but perhaps all it needed was a good fan cleaning. I think I cleaned the new fan before installing it, so maybe the clean fan will keep it cool enough to keep it from shutting off. Unfortunately, my mobile's health has gone down. Not only is my mobile unable to read Ext4 and loosing files on FAT, it's now also claiming that my FAT SD card is blank or nonexistent. This is ridiculous. Why has my mobile suddenly started failing on me recently?

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

We're almost done at the school.

Day 00470: Sunday, 2016 June 19

This morning, we unloaded the van of last night's load, then took three more loads from the school. We've finished removing everything that needs to be removed, save for some paperwork that will be needed there tomorrow. Our plan is to pick it up tomorrow, finish some last-minute tasks (such as returning library books and checking out of the classroom for the year), then head to Portland or Salem to search for a place to rent. It sounds like we'll be gone for a few days though. I've finally finished catching up (I've been behind in writing weblog entries for about a month until today, having to write them from notes I took on their respective days, which is why I've done zero work on include.d for a while), and now I'll probably end up behind again. There's a chance that instead of house hunting, we'll instead just come home after picking up Cyrus and Vanessa, then work on setting up for our yard sale, so I may or may not actually disappear for a few days.

The landlords stopped by again while we were away. It seems that they've erected a new fence to replace one that was old, rotted, and had blown down in the wind. They don't seem to actually care about the quality though. They didn't anchor it well, just burying the posts in the sand without any cement to hold them down. They only need the fence to remain up long enough for the house to sell. After that, they simply don't care.

I was going to work on include.d as soon as I caught up with my journal entry writing, but now that I might not be here for a few days, I'm just not feeling it. I don't want to jump back into that project knowing that I'll likely be kept away from it after I start. I'll lose my train of thought. If I wait until we return, I'll probably do better and more consistent work.

Before turning in for the night, my mother and I headed out to the hills to search for bullet shells. I didn't find all that many (only three), but my mother found a couple pockets full. I wonder if our new residence will have woodland places such as this to go searching at. I think my mother might go crazy (er, crazier) if they can't get out and walk among the trees every few days.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Softer

Day 00471: Monday, 2016 June 20

My mother said that there was nothing left for me to do at the school, so they departed alone to finish up their business there while I stayed home to work on dishes. It took much longer than I'd anticipated though, and I was a bit worried that they'd taken off for Springfield without me. As it turned out, my mother never meant to stay at the school so long, several unexpected tasks had just come up. Once they got back, we loaded up the van, and headed out to Springfield to drop off stuff and pick up Vanessa and Cyrus.

On the way there, we got stuck in traffic on the highway that'd come to a complete stop. We feared that another motor vehicle accident was to blame, but it turned out to be road work. My mother was relieved, saying that they'd rather sit through a thirty-minute delay caused by road work than a ten-minute delay caused by a traffic accident. That was quite a shock for me! I can't seem to locate the incident in this journal, so I'm unsure if it predated the journal or if I just failed to mention it, but my mother once felt quite the opposite. Much to my horror, when there was a large traffic delay in Springfield, they'd been quite disappointed about not at least getting to see an accident at the end of it. Perhaps Coos Bay has changed my mother. Along that same train of thought, my mother seems like a much softer person today than they have been in the recent past. Working in an awful school has been doing a number on them, but now that they're out, maybe they're starting to regain their sanity in part. We ended up taking a different route home to bypass the roadwork. While it was nice to know that the cause was benign, there still wasn't any point in us possibly sitting through the delay again.

While in Springfield, I noticed that the Mormons had left me a greeting card. What do they want with me? I was happy to see that they have my old address on file instead of my new address, but they left no contact information of their own. So basically, a random church that I have no affiliation with has reached out to me, but but hasn't provided any way for me to actually respond. What good does that do them?

I spoke with Vanessa, and they've now told me what they really wanted all along. They said they'd give anything to remain in Coos Bay with their friends. However, while our mother had probed for such information on many occasions, Vanessa hadn't told them such. Our mother said that they'd have been willing to suffer through their unbearable job for four more years if needed to get Vanessa through school, but as Vanessa didn't communicate that this was wanted, our mother quit their job to look for one less miserable. Vanessa sacrificed getting to remain with their friends to make our mother less unhappy. Hopefully having our mother in a happier and saner state will also aid in Vanessa's happiness. It's too late to unquit their job at this point, there's no going back. Vanessa also mentioned wanting to set up a pair of weblogs, one about helping humanity and one containing creative writing works by Vanessa themself, but wasn't sure even how to set one up. I suggested finding a Wordpress host, as Wordpress is free software and gratis hosts are available. It also helps that Vanessa was required to use Wordpress for a school-assigned weblog during the school year before last, so Vanessa's familiar with using the software. Nudging Vanessa towards Wordpress seemed successful, and and it's likely that Vanessa will end up hosting with //wordpress.org because they're the easiest to find Wordpress host.

On the way home, we stopped by the site of the dead porcupine because our mother wanted to show it off to Cyrus and Vanessa. That seems kind of morbid to me, but whatever. Because we were already in the hills at this point, we also gathered up some bullet shells before heading home.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Slough

Day 00472: Tuesday, 2016 June 21

Cyrus' computer overheats all the time, so I offered to try to clean out the fan for Cyrus. It worked on my machine, it might work on their's. However, I couldn't get the fan out to properly clean it and I couldn't find any dust in it from the only angles I could access the fan from. It then occurred to me that Cyrus' laptop has been overheating since the day Cyrus got it, and it was a refurbished laptop. A clogged fan wasn't likely the problem. I did add two gigabytes of RAM to the machine for Cyrus' trouble though, and to get it out of my RAM stash. I have several RAM sticks still, but I never have any machines to put them in.

For a couple days now, a friend's been trying to get me to change the name "Margret" to use the spelling "Margaret" in some past entries on this journal. I've been refusing on the grounds that "Margret" is a legitimate name as well and the name holder was introduced to me as "Ma-ry-Mar-gret", not "Ma-ry-Mar-gar-et". Unless people are pronouncing the name phonetically, I saw no reason to assume that the non-phonetic spelling was the correct one over the phonetic spelling. This friend is persistent though, and located an old Bunker Hill staff page with the name spelled out. This staff page appears to be from when Bunker Hill Elementary was going to be reopened, an endeavor that was canceled, but there's no mistaking the photograph that goes along with the name; it's the same person. I've not amended my past entries to use the correct spelling of this person's name.

I took a trip into town to cancel my dental appointment and speak with the two banks that service accounts on my behalf. Canceling the appointment went exactly as expected of course, but I had mixed results with the banks. In truth, I wanted to close the accounts, but I feel like I need a reason to do so. The We don't know where we're going yet, but the assumption is that we're going to Portland or Salem, with Salem being preferred. Being in Salem would put us much closer to our mother's Portland-based family than we are now, but would lessen the risks of unexpected house guests that we'd likely have in Portland itself. Bank of the Cascades has branches in both cities, so I didn't cancel my account with them. I don't really have any beef with them anyway. Banner Bank on the other hand has a branch in Portland but not Salem. I really want this account closed, but I'm unsure if I should actually close it yet, so I didn't.

Next, I went home to grab bottles to return for deposit, which I was planning to take alone. Cyrus invited themself along though, despite knowing that I hate taking bottles back in a group. If I'm doing it, it's a waste of the group's time to come with me. If the group is doing it, it's a waste of *my* time to be there. Unknown to Cyrus at the time though, I just needed an excuse to leave the house and get to that particular store, which also offers dog tag engravings, so it worked out. With Cyrus already coming, I invited Vanessa as well so Vanessa wouldn't feel left out. There was only one open bottle return machine present, so there was no way that all of us could be of any use at once, so I left the two of them to deal with the bottles while I went in to get an engraved dog tag. Unfortunately, lower-case letters were not available for engraving. That means that I couldn't include any URI on the tag that contains case-sensitive components that needed to be lower case. I'd planned on adding an email address and XMPP address among other options, but that was off the table now. These URIs contain path components. Userinfo components would be equally problematic. Instead, I had engraved only my name and the URI HTTPS://Y.ST./. There wasn't any space for the delimiting angle brackets, but it's good enough.

At the end of the day, Vanessa, Cyrus, our mother, and I went out to hike through a slough and through its surrounding forest for two hours. It was a very beautiful area, though the final half hour was difficult. We were in a rush to get out before dark, so we had to take the most direct route: straight up what was probably the steepest hill there. The paths in both the slough and the forest were very nice and (aside from the steep path out) were quite easy to traverse. The forest paths were nice and smooth, free of debris, large roots, and small vegetation. This was despite the fact that on either side of the path, highly-dense plant life was everywhere. Through the slow, well-kept boardwalks were provided. They passed through what was probably the densest field of skunk cabbage that I'd ever seen.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

"Bowling dollars"

Day 00473: Wednesday, 2016 June 22

I went out for a sandwich today, seeing as my mother can't stand the scent of my cooking and there's nothing vegan to eat around the house that doesn't require cooking. On the way out, I rode too close to a telephone pole that happened to have a nail sticking out; it caught on my shirt and ripped it, in addition to hurting my arm slightly. I should really try not to ride so close to obstacles, but it'd also be nice if people removed their nails when they were done with them; they're a needless hazard. When I got home, I heard that my mother would get weird as usual if they knew I'd gone out for food. They hate my diet and I don't need the fact that there's nothing to eat at home rubbed in their face. With that in mind, I lied about my trip when they asked. I told them that I went out to cancel my dental appointment, which I actually did yesterday. The results weren't what I'd hoped for. Instead of dismissing the issue, my mother said to have the dental office call me if an appointment opened up this week. First, that puts me on the hook, waiting for a blasted telephone call for an appointment that I won't actually get! Second, I despise the telephone number system and won't give out a working number to anyone, save for a potential employer. I do have the land line number that I could have given out, but that line was set up for job hunting only. I would rather avoid having an appointment at all than have to have anything to do with the telephone number system. I'm just going to silently ignore these orders. My mother will never know. In addition to being overstressed by the move (so they'll likely forget about the appointment entirely), the period of time in which the orders are relevant is so short that no one would call anyway. My mother knows that I hate telephones, though I don't think that they comprehend why. Asking me to set anything up that both relates to myself and involves the telephone number system is unreasonable.

We hiked around in the slough area again for another two hours, but this time, we planned a bit better. We were able to get out in time without having to take the steep, uphill shortcut. After leaving, we went to a local bowling alley to get a bite to eat. My mother's team had won some "bowling dollars" from some knowledge-based competition and my mother had been designated as the receiver of the prize in full. We're not sure why that was, as each "bowling dollar" had been printed on a separate sheet of paper and the prize could easily be split amongst the team members, but now they needed to be spent before we leave town as not to go to waste.

Tomorrow, we plan to set up for our yard sale, but we'll see how that goes. We always get delayed for one reason or another.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mother is so stubborn (like Vanessa and me).

Day 00476: Saturday, 2016 June 25

I mostly ran the yard sale again today. Yesterday, I didn't really have anything that I could do between customers, but this time, I was more prepared. I'm not sure how much longer we'll have Internet access, so I started my much-needed Debian downgrade to Stable. While customers were around, I went out to help them and my machine set up parts of the system, but while they were gone, I came back inside and entered more information into the installer. Strangely, the installer couldn't connect to the Internet over Wi-Fi. It found both my wireless card and the wireless access point with no difficulty (displaying the name of our access point and other local access points in a list), but couldn't actually download anything for some reason. I'm not sure what the deal was. Installing over an Ethernet cable instead worked though, so that's what I did. Once the system was set up, Wi-Fi worked out of the box without any extra effort. Strange. What's up with the installer then?

My mother wanted me to create a Facebook account and use it to post about the yard sale, not wanting the address to be associated with their own name. Yet somehow, my mother's against me trying to have privacy myself on most occasions. Why didn't my mother just set up the second account themself? In any case, I figured I'd comply, knowing that Facebook would demand a telephone number, and I'd give Facebook my mother's number and show my mother how annoying it is that companies demand telephone numbers. Then maybe, my mother would understand a bit better that I don't want companies to have a telephone number on record for me. My mother would care because my mother doesn't want to be contacted, while I instead don't want to be identified by a number instead of a name. It wouldn't be quite the same, but it might get enough of the message across. However, much to my delight and surprise, Facebook demanded that I present them with photographic ID instead, not even asking for a telephone number! Not only would my mother not be interested in having their identity linked to the address even further, there's probably not even time for Facebook to process the ID! Facebooks is such a bunch of privacy- and freedom-haters, I swear. Obviously, the plan to create a Facebook account in order to advertise the sale on Facebook was canceled.

Our mother made the claim that Vanessa gets their stubbornness from me today, which of course makes little sense. I explained that my stubbornness comes from our mother, so while it's most likely that Vanessa inherited or learned stubbornness from them and not me, even if Vanessa did learn it from me, it would have meant indirectly learning it from our mother. Our mother retorted that they themself are stubborn in cases that stubbornness is positive, but that Vanessa and I are stubborn about stupid things. I explained that in many, many cases, our mother is the one being stubborn to the point of idiocy, so they asked for an example. Our mother retains jumbled details of everything in their head a all times, so they can come out with examples, even if only flawed ones often, for anything, and seems to expect others to be able to do the same. I didn't have an example right away though, as I don't keep such things in RAM; I have more important things on my mind. After a while, a recent example hit me though: our discussion on even and odd dollar amounts. This started mother off arguing again that they were right about even and odd dollar amounts, despite the fact that even and odd dollar amounts weren't even relevent to today's conversation. Of course, I dropped the issue again right away, but bringing it up had successfully proved my point: my mother is stubborn to the point of idiocy. If Vanessa got their stubbornness from me, it was still indirectly from our mother, and I most certainly got it from our mother.

Vanessa put our clay pigeon collection (that we gathered over several trips out in the hills hunting for bullet shells) out on the lawn, arranged into groups. I misunderstood the groups though. While there were actually one hundred twenty-eight pigeons, I thought that there were about half that. The pigeons were labeled as costing one dollar for every twenty pigeons, so sixty pigeons would have been three dollars. Someone offered me two dollars for all of them, so I took it, figuring that it meant we'd have them all gone for sure. The person later gave me an extra dollar for them, so we were up to three dollars for them, but our mother was frustrated that I'd sold them so cheaply. Upon my later calculation though, I found that I'd only cost us three dollars. They were old weathered pigeons too, we'd just found them in the hills. Our mother had been trying to sell them for almost full price (I'd looked up how much they cost online before our mother priced them), so anyone that knew what they were talking about wouldn't have bought them at such prices. I will be more careful in the future though. If my mother would rather deal with the clay disks staying around when we don't have space for them than getting a little bit of money for them, so be it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I've been accepted!

Day 00477: Sunday, 2016 June 26

My mother decided to post about our yard sale using their own Facebook account after all. Apparently, using an advertising method other than Facebook isn't an option to them. How effective is Facebook for local yard sale listing, anyway? It doesn't seem to me like it'd be of much value. In any case, my mother was dead set on getting the yard sale listed on Facebook, so that's exactly what they got.

Vanessa and Cyrus took turns watching the yard sale while I cleaned out the cooler, then the refrigerator and freezer. I was instructed that anything freezer burnt or unimportant should be thrown out, so that's what I did. I found *so much* freezer burnt meat that had to be removed. The meat-eaters in this house don't eat the food that they buy. These are lives that they've had snuffed out, and they haven't even bothered to make use of them. What a waste. If it had been vegetables, I'd have eaten them myself long ago. We seriously don't keep enough vegetables in the house.

I also checked in on my University of [REDACTED] application online. I've been anxiously waiting for a response from them, but hadn't yet. I've been accepted! Frustrated that they didn't email me about my acceptance as they said they would, I checked my email, and sure enough, they sent me a letter informing me three days ago - I've just been too busy to check my email in that time period. It's a good thing that I checked now though, as I was expected to respond by the thirtieth of this month, confirming my enrollment and choosing a starting term. I chose the September term; the November term was the only other available option. My mother wanted to know if my credits from my last school would transfer to my new school. I wasn't sure how to break it to them that I'd rather start fresh than be associated with that terrible other school. They weren't supportive and they were not understanding. I don't want their name on my degree, and if possible, I'd like to have my record with them stricken. However, if I were to say that, it'd likely start an argument. Thankfully, I located information while skimming University of [REDACTED]'s terms of service indicating that they do not take transfer credits at all at this time, from any school. I can get what I need without any hassling from my mother.

At the end of the day, we bagged up everything that we need to be rid of (save for the refrigerator) so that we can haul it off and donate it tomorrow.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Does my mother have no empathy?

Day 00479: Tuesday, 2016 June 28

We were going to rent a trailer from the moving van company for twenty-four hours, but we couldn't find our trailer hitch. The main problem is that we have our belongings spread out across two houses still, so whenever we need something, there's a chance that it's too far away to reach. Our only option was to take a load to Springfield in the van (minivan, not moving van) without the added space provided by the trailer. On the way to Springfield, our mother seemed quite surprised that Cyrus wasn't their usual chipper self. Does our mother not understand that other people have feelings? Our mother thoroughly railed on us both yesterday, why would either of us be chipper? I've learned to keep my emotions under wraps around our mother, but for Cyrus, it's all out there on their sleeve. Cyrus seemed lifeless and emotionally drained. In any sane world, why would Cyrus be any other way, given the circumstances?

Once in the Springfield house, I felt like I was mostly standing around trying to figure out what to do. The goal was to move things that we were not keeping out of the garage to make space to store things that we were keeping. However, Cyrus and especially I already thinned down to the point where nothing in this old house belong to us. Everything left either belongs to our mother or is "family" gear; in other words, objects that my mother prefers not to think of as being exclusively their own, but that they themselves hold the exclusive power to decide whether it's being kept or not. Cyrus and I did our best though, and the three of us finished up our task.

As we were heading out, I noticed a partial photograph of my father in the garbage. My mother had cut out themself, Vivian, and me from the image, leaving only the background and our father! My mother has always liked to rewrite history, claiming that things were different than they really were. I suppose doctoring old photographs is just an extension of that tendency.

On our way out of town, we met up with Robert, one of my mother's friends. Robert had offered to give us their trailer hitch. The thing is, they didn't even want the trailer hitch. It had come on their current vehicle and the only reason it was still there was that it was held in place by a lock, not one of the usual pins. Robert had tried to cut the lock in the past to remove it, but hadn't succeeded. Today, Robert tried again to cut the lock, failed, then got their neighbour to help them out. Despite not wanting the thing, it was awfully nice of Robert to go through the trouble to give us the trailer hitch. It'll save us a lot of money in getting a new one.

Heading back to Coos Bay, our mother talked about how Robert and their partner Heather seem to be going through a rough patch, relationship-wise. Our mother thinks that they don't make a good pair and that this is going to be the final straw that breaks them up. Heather and Robert married in Oregon, but since then, Heather's been trying to get Robert and themself moved to Nevada. Robert doesn't like Nevada, it's too much of a desert, while Heather doesn't like western Oregon because it isn't a desert. Our mother says that people should marry in the place that they want to be; after all, that's where you'll find others that want to be there as well. Honestly, I can see the logic in that, but is our mother really one to talk? Our mother married a man in California after promising the man that they'd not try to move out of California. The man didn't want to leave the state. Later though, our mother demanded that they leave anyway, breaking their promise. That man, our father, says that they're happy that they were convinced to come to Oregon by our mother. However, that doesn't change the fact that my mother has no room to speak ill of Heather. At least Heather, to the best of my knowledge, made no such promise not to move.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The server is now down indefinitely.

Day 00480: Wednesday, 2016 June 29

While working on some last-minute packing, I finally peeled the stickers off of my old FSF membership card USB drive. The card/USB drive hybrid idea is an interesting one, so the drive itself is worth keeping, but the FSF actively supports the creation on nonfree works. As such, I can't really support the FSF in good conscience.

Having gotten our beds and dressers out of the way, we can now see that the wall's been damaged behind Cyrus' dresser and the floor's been torn up under my bed. I'm not sure what's with the damage behind the dresser, but my guess is that the floor got torn up at some point when the bed was being moved near the beginning of our stay there. Our cat was freaked out by the move and kept hiding under the bed, so we kept bringing it out to try to show it that everything was okay. I offered to pay the security deposit on the house, which seemed to keep our mother from completely blowing their top. It's not an inexpensive bill to foot though.

I shut down //cepo.local. today to get it packed up, though I'd forgotten that the server had been being used for DNS requests. The last computer on the local network that isn't using Tor couldn't make proper use of the Internet due to my oversight! It was a quick fix once I located the problem though, so no real harm done.

One of the landlords stopped by today thinking that they'd check us out of the house a day early. For some reason, they thought we'd be completely out of the house, even though we've paid through the end of the month. After seeing that we weren't even close to being out and that they'd have to come by later, they left.

We had to have the front door open so we could move furniture out, so Frances (our cat) escaped for a bit. Frances has a tendency to try to get out, but then once out, cower because the outside world is intimidating. Catching the cat was easy as usual, but Frances had managed to cover its belly in burrs that needed to be picked out. With its fur being so long, getting the burrs out itself wouldn't have been an easy task, so I picked them out for it.

Cyrus went over and talked to the trucker next door and ask them to help us move the moving van and its vehicle-towing trailer later. The trucker agreed to help. When we were moving in, that same trucker helped us too, though that time, they'd offered. Our mother also managed to talk the moving van company into letting us use two of their storage units instead of the promised one unit, so we should have enough space, I hope.

We continued loading up the moving van for most of the day, then took another load to Springfield on the minivan. My mother asked me to back their computer files up onto a USB drive tomorrow. I planned to do it tonight, but by the time we arrived home again, I was too tired. As long as I get them backed up tomorrow though, it'll be fine. Many of these files are needed for job seeking, so as we won't have Internet access for a while, the USB drive is needed so that a borrowed computer with an Internet connection will do. Tomorrow, Cyrus and our mother will take another load to Springfield in the minivan. I'll probably use that opportunity to close down my bank account and pay my mobile bill, then I'll get back to work and continue loading up the moving van.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

No concern for anyone or anything

Day 00481: Thursday, 2016 June 30

I backed up my mother's files aside from their software settings onto a USB drive to lend them. I would have backed up the settings too (why not?), but the USB drive that I'm lending them isn't large enough to store the settings along with the other files. The SHYDRIVE would be large enough, but of course my mother's Windows-based machine is too stupid to read and write to a decent file system and I can't stand the though of formatting the SHYDRIVE back to something atrocious such as FAT. For that matter, the machine that my mother will later borrow access to may very be running Windows as well, so even if my mother was on Debian, a FAT USB drive might be a better option. My mother only needed very specific files backed up though, so the missing settings files won't be a problem. I mainly backed up everything simply because I don't know where my mother keeps each of the files that they wanted and I didn't want to leave them without something that they needed.

It turns out that our mother decided not to go to Springfield with Cyrus this morning, so I didn't have the time I needed to close my bank account and pay my mobile bill when I was expecting to, though I got a chance to do the former later in the day. Our mother and I took three loads to a local storage unit in Coos Bay; during the second trip, my mother stopped at the mall to pick up sodas for themself, so I took that chance to run my own errands there. The account closing went well, but when I stopped to pay my mobile bill, I couldn't find my mobile. My mobile stores my account information, so without that, they wouldn't be able to access my account to deposit money. I didn't want to slow my mother down too much, so I hurried out instead of digging in my bag enough. I later found the mobile in my bag, but it was too late at that point. I'll just have to pay the bill from Springfield later.

In the face of great temptation, I prevailed. I wanted to pick up a portable gaming system while I was at the mall, but I refrained. I likely won't have Internet access for quite a while, so it'd be nice to have something to do while I wait to know where we're going to live so I can apply for jobs.

While packing up things to take to the storage unit, my mother tried to dump the gasoline out of the lawn mower and into the storm gutter, where it'd be drained likely into the ocean. Does my mother have no concern for the environment at all!? I suppose that I already knew this about them, but their lack of caring still often takes me by surprise. Cyrus and I managed to have scratch the top of our dining room table when loading it, though the table had already been scarred before we moved by rotten potatoes that had been left sitting on it, dissolving the the finish, so at least we didn't ruin a perfect table.

My mother instructed me to try to hide the damage to the floor under my bed leg using rubber cement; I reluctantly complied. First of all, that seems dishonest. We should be upfront with the landlords, then I should pay the security deposit. I also can't stand working with rubber cement, though that's beside the point. In any case, the floor does look much better now, though if the landlords do any sort of inspection, they'll surely see the tear.

My mother applied for a duel-language immersion job with one of the schools; it sounds like they'd be teaching the English half. Within an hour of submitting the application, the school was already emailing my mother's references! If they land this job, things should stabilize for now and we can begin rebuilding our uprooted lives.

The other day, my mother tasked me with filing our change of address with the post office to have our mail forwarded back to our former residence. Later that day, they asked if I'd done it yet, but they knew very well that I hadn't had time to get to the post office to pick up the forms yet, as I'd been home loading the moving van all day. I reminded them of that, so they replied that they thought that the forms had been online. That's a reasonable assumption, as most things these days are online, but I explained that no, I'd used paper forms when we moved to Coos Bay. In truth, I'd tried to find an online form before, but it was on the post office website. As the United States Post Office maliciously discriminates against Tor users, I'd had to walk in and ask for the paper ones. At first, the post office wouldn't give them to me, saying to fill out the form online, but when I showed them on my mobile that their website was blocking me, they handed over the paper forms that I needed. I said I'd get to the post office to pick up the forms when I had time, but instead, my mother said they'd pick the forms up at some point when they were going past the post office anyway. It had been a while since the last time that I'd gotten the forms, so it'd slipped my mind that the post office workers might try to direct my mother to the online form as they did me. Indeed, the post office workers said to use the online form. Had I been there, I could have shown them the problem again, but instead, my mother just reported to me that the forms were online after all as they'd originally thought. I explained again that I needed the paper forms, then explained that the online form was nonfunctional, but they decided to fill out the online form themself as the post office had requested. It seems though that they charge a dollar to fill it out online! In addition to the paper forms being far more accessible, they don't come with a fee attached. Next time I'm at a post office, I should check to make sure that the paper forms are still available. I'll show them again that their website's broken, then see if they'll hand them over. It's not my fault that they want to block my only source of Internet access, and some people don't even have Internet access to begin with. There must be a non-Internet form for the rare people that need it.

Our mother brought up to us that we may argue, but our arguments aren't as bad as those of other families. I find that highly improbable! Do most heads-of-household threaten to disown their children if the children cut their hair? Do they threaten to evict their children it they continue to have a relationship with their other parent? Do they make threats if the other family members don't give in to every little, noxious, and petty demand made? I don't think so. We don't fight back as we fear them, so they don't see how bad it is, I guess. They lack kindness and empathy. We never know which threats are real and not, and the threats come out of our mother as easily as their very breath. On at least one occasion, Vivian did get disowned and evicted. We can't take that chance, as we don't have the support network that Vivian does. These fights are horrid and there's no way to even win.

Later in the day, my mother commented that they don't know how I can survive as a vegan. They like to say that every once in a while. I replied that I survive barely, so they continued that vegetables don't really provide much energy. I dropped it on them that I indeed don't have energy because they don't want me to cook. Without a decent meal, I indeed don't feel well. I've been drained of energy for quite a while now. Though I didn't say it, it's not even like they care what shape I'm in. They are put off by the smell of my cooking, and as a result, I don't get to even get decent nutrition. How can you claim to love someone while choosing their constant lethargia over you having to smell food that you don't personally find appetizing? Either my mother's sense of smell is off the charts (which they'll argue isn't true) or they have zero concern for my well-being. I suppose I already know that, but it hurts to think about. My mother loves the *idea* of their children, but not their children themselves.

Tonight, our mother took another load in the minivan to Springfield, leaving Cyrus and I to continue work on the house. We were supposed to be out by the end of today, but it looks like we'll be taking some of tomorrow as well.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.